hindifire.com 2017-12-10

# Privacy policy - Hindifire

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how  
 their 'Personally  
 identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and  
 information security,  
is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or  
 locate a single  
person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a  
clear  
 understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable  
 Information  
 in accordance with our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name,  
 email address,  
 mailing address or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form or enter  
 information on  
 our site.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up  
for our  
 newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain  
 other site  
 features in the following ways:

**•**  To personalize user's experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product  
 offerings  
 in which you are most interested.

**•**  To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.

**•**  To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.

**How do we protect visitor information?**

We do not use Malware Scanning.

We do not use an SSL certificate

**•**  We only provide articles and information, we never ask for personal  
 or private information like  
email addresses, or credit card numbers.

**Do we use 'cookies'?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your  
computer's hard drive  
 through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's  
systems to recognize  
 your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use  
 cookies to help us  
 remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us  
 understand your  
 preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you  
 with improved  
 services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and  
 site interaction so  
that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**•**  Keep track of advertisements.

**•**  Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer  
 better  
 site experiences  
and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this  
 information  
on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or  
 you can choose to  
 turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings.  
 Each browser is a  
 little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify  
your cookies.

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It won't affect the users experience  
 that make  
 your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.

However, you can still place orders .

**Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally  
 identifiable information  
unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting  
 partners and other  
parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so  
 long as those  
parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information  
 when we believe  
 release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others'  
 rights, property, or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties  
 for marketing,  
 advertising, or other uses.

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services  
 on our website.  
 These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have  
no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless,  
we seek  
 to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles.  
They are  
 put in place to provide a positive experience for  
 users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the  
 DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other  
sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the  
 Google ad and  
 content network privacy policy.

**We have implemented the following:**

**•**  Remarketing with Google AdSense

**•**  DoubleClick Platform Integration

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use  
 first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics  
 cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie)  
 or other third-party identifiers  
 together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions,  
and other ad service functions  
as they relate to our website.

Opting out:  
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the  
 Google Ad Settings page.  
 Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page  
or permanently  
 using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**California  Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites  
and online services  
 to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to  
 require a person or  
company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites  
collecting personally  
 identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy  
policy on its website  
 stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom  
 it is being shared,  
 and to comply with this policy. - See more  
 at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page,  
 or as a minimum on the  
 first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy', and can be easily be found  
on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:

**•**  On our Privacy Policy Page

Users are able to change their personal information:

**•**  By emailing us

**How does our site handle do not track signals?**

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a  
 Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?**

It's also important to note that we allow third party behavioral tracking

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under  
13, the Children's  
Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal  
 Trade Commission, the  
 nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells  
 out what operators of  
 websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the  
 United States and the  
 concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection  
 laws around  
 the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be  
 implemented is  
 critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following**  
**  responsive action,**  
**  should a data breach occur:**

We will notify the users via email

**•**  Within 7 business days

We will notify the users via in site notification

**•**  Within 7 business days

We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals  
 have a right to pursue  
legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere  
 to the law. This  
principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data  
 users, but also that  
individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute  
 non-compliance  
 by data processors.

For any issues contact at www.Hindifire.com
